erikkimsey.github.io github.com/erikkimsey

Erik KimseyFrontend Engineer / Creative Engineer

Frontend Engineer with over 3+ years of combined professional experience, with expertise using *Javascript, React.js*, and *React Native*. Experience collaborating with multi-disciplinary teams, bringing software from start to production. Initially self-taught, with continued education in: full-stack software engineering and graphic design, and a BA in Philosophy. Tenacious, entrepreneurial, keen aesthetic sense, and end-user oriented.

Skill Set

Expert: React.js • Typescript • Javascript • React Native • CSS/HTML5 • C#

Advanced: Next.js • Redux • SASS • Node.js • Angular • SQLite • Python • Django

Familiar: Docker • Kubernetes • D3.js • Three.js • GraphQL • Plotly.js

Software: Adobe Illustrator · Adobe Photoshop · Figma

Work Experience

Full-Stack Engineer / Founder - Moxie

2021 - 2022

- Created Moxie's user-stories, upon which I architected Moxie's frontend structure and backend schemas.
- Engineered 2 prototypes of Moxie, 3 scenes each; first, using React and again using C# / Unity3D.
- Engineered 20+ core features using C# and Javascript / React.
- Created over 50 visual, audio and UI elements (incl. 3D models, UI graphics, and shaders).
- · Drafted Moxie's initial business and marketing plan.

Frontend Engineer - Sartography / University of Virginia

2020-2021

- Using Typescript and React, engineered 100% of SkillSTAR's user-interface.
- Reduced project costs by over 70%, by performing the roles of SkillSTAR's UI designer and project manager.
- · Collaborating with a multi-disciplinary team, refined SkillSTAR's user-story and business logic.
- Implemented the "chaining educational model" as a recursive algorithm for skill discovery and learning reinforcement.
- · Using UX design best-practices, created 5 graphic assets used throughout SkillSTAR.
- Collaborating with backend engineers, using Node.js, SQL and Python, engineered requisite database schema and Rest API endpoints.

Full-Stack Engineer - Chatwise	2019
Frontend (Mobile) Engineer - RealmChain	2019
Frontend (Mobile) Engineer - Connect Our Kids	2019
Frontend Engineer - NextLevelSh*t (Germany)	2018
Javascript Engineer - Cosaic (ChartIQ) / eToro	2016 - 2017
Studio Recording Technician - Rosetta Stone	2012 - 2016

Education

Full-Stack Software Engineering, CE - BloomTech (Lambda School) 2018 - 2019 Computer Science, Post-BS - Oregon State University 2015 - 2016 Graphic & Web Design, CE - Blue Ridge Community College 2014 - 2015 Philosophy, BA James Madison University 2006 - 2010

Accolades / Volunteer

EMT Basic - Harrisonburg Volunteer Rescue Squad
Phi Sigma Tau - Philosophy Honors Society member, JMU
Coding Tutor - Skyline Middle School, HCPS
Founder / Director - Club of Creative Writing, BRCC